Guide to the Peter Straub Papers MSS.185
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series XI: Audio, 1994; 2000; 2004; undated
  Series XI contains reel-to-reel magnetic tapes, cassette tapes, CDs, shellac LPs, and glass LPs that feature audio recordings of speeches given by political figures such as Winston Churchill and programs featuring interviews with Straub.
  - Subseries A: Access Copies
    Conditions Governing Access
    Audio materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - Subseries B: Originals, 1994; 2000; 2004; undated
    Subseries B contains original audio elements.
    - Merry Christmas to the Straubs Love [Perceval], undated; ID: 185.0002 (Box 61, Media ID: 185.0002)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Audiocassettes.
    - Cabinet #1 (NYC) Winter 2000, ID: 185.0003 (Box 61, Media ID: 185.0003)
      Compact discs.
    - Live at the Ear, 1994; ID: 185.0004 (Box 61, Media ID: 185.0004)
    - LD & the New Criticism "Tragic Realism", 2005; ID: 185.0005 (Box 61, Media ID: 185.0005)
    - WNYC Peter Straub, undated; ID: 185.0006 (Box 61, Media ID: 185.0006)
    - Glass Discs of Winston Churchill Speeches, 09/06/1943, 01/27/1946; ID: 185.0008 A (Box 67, Media ID: 185.0008 A, Media ID: 185.0007 A, Media ID: 185.0010 A, Media ID: 185.0009 A, Media ID: 185.0012 A, Media ID: 185.0011 A)
      Phonograph records. [Glass discs]
    - Shellac Discs of Winston Churchill Speeches, 05/13/1945 (Box 67, Media ID: 185.0019 A, Media ID: 185.0018 A, Media ID: 185.0020 A, Media ID: 185.0015 A, Media ID: 185.0014 A, Media ID: 185.0017 A, Media ID: 185.0016 A, Media ID: 185.0013 A)
      Phonograph records. [Shellac discs]
    - Mac Arthur's Speech [1], undated; ID: 185.0021 (Box 68, Media ID: 185.0021)
      Magnetic tapes. [paper based, reel to reel]
    - Mac Arthur's Speech [2], undated; ID: 185.0022 (Box 68, Media ID: 185.0022)
    - Mac Arthur's Speech [3], undated; ID: 185.0023 (Box 68, Media ID: 185.0023)
    - This is a Churchill Speech Delivered at Quebec, undated; ID: 185.0024 (Box 68, Media ID: 185.0024)
    - Churchill's Edinburgh Speech, undated; ID: 185.0025 (Box 68, Media ID: 185.0025)
    - Churchill's Speech, undated; ID: 185.0026 (Box 68, Media ID: 185.0026)
    - Churchill's Mass. Inst of Technology Speech. Part Two, undated; ID: 185.0027 (Box 68, Media ID: 185.0027)
  - Subseries C: Separated Paper Material, undated
    Subseries C contains paper materials that were seperated from the audio materials.
    - Separated Paper Material, 1943-1946 (Box 66)
- Series XII: Video, undated
  Series XII contains one video cassette featuring the show "Prisoners of Gravity," a Canadian news program from the early 1990s that explored themes in speculative fiction.
  - Subseries A: Access Copies, undated
    Video materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - Subseries B: Originals, undated
    Subseries B contains original video elements.
    - Prisoners of Gravity; for Peter; The Sandman, undated; ID: 185.0001 (Box 61, Media ID: 185.0001)
      Videocassettes.
- Series XIII: Data Media, 1981-1994
  Items in this series are arranged chronologically.
  Series XIII contains 3.5" floppy disks of compter programs.
  - Subseries A: Access Copies, undated
    Born-digital materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - Subseries B: Originals, 1981-1994
    Subseries B contains original data media elements.
    - Norton Rescue Disc, undated; ID: 185.3.0001 (Box 61, Media ID: 185.3.0001)
    - AST Research, Inc., 1990-1992; ID: 185.3.0003 (Box 61, Media ID: 185.3.0003, Media ID: 185.3.0002, Media ID: 185.3.0005, Media ID: 185.3.0004, Media ID: 185.3.0007, Media ID: 185.3.0006, Media ID: 185.3.0008, Media ID: 185.3.0009)
    - The Norton Desktop for Windows, 1993 (Box 61, Media ID: 185.3.0010, Media ID: 185.3.0011, Media ID: 185.3.0012, Media ID: 185.3.0013, Media ID: 185.3.0014, Media ID: 185.3.0015, Media ID: 185.3.0016)
    - Dos 6-22, 1981-1994; ID: 185.3.0019 (Box 61, Media ID: 185.3.0019, Media ID: 185.3.0018, Media ID: 185.3.0017)
    - Windows for Workgroups 3.11, 1981-1994 (Box 61, Media ID: 185.3.0026, Media ID: 185.3.0027, Media ID: 185.3.0020, Media ID: 185.3.0021, Media ID: 185.3.0022, Media ID: 185.3.0023, Media ID: 185.3.0024, Media ID: 185.3.0025)
    - Microsoft Intellipoint Professional, 10/13/1994; ID: 185.3.0028 (Box 61, Media ID: 185.3.0028)
    - Kodak Picture CD, 1981-1994; ID: 185.3.0029 A (Box 61, Media ID: 185.3.0029 A)
  - Subseries C: Separated Paper Material, 05/21/2006
    Includes paper materials that were sepereated from the computer files.
    - 185.3.0029 B, 05/21/2006 (Box 61)
- Series XIV: Objects (Box 62)
  Series XIV contains objects from the collection.
  - Leather-bound collage journal, undated (Box 62, Object ID: 185.2.0001)
  - Various conference name tags, 2005; 2006; undated (Box 62, Object ID: 185.2.0002)
  - Drum brushes, undated (Box 62, Object ID: 185.2.0003)
  - Ruppert's Bar/Resaurant matchbox, undated (Box 62, Object ID: 185.2.0004)
- Series XVI: 2022 Accretion, 1990-2021; 11 Linear Feet in 21 manuscript boxes and 2 half manuscript boxes
  This accretion to the Peter Straub Papers consists primarily of manuscripts in various stages, with the works Hello Jack, A Dark Matter, The Sylark, and American Fantastic Tales especially well represented. This accretion also includes correspondence, press materials, calendars, and a small amount of photographs.
  Appraisal
  Materials with personal financial and medical information, as well as recommendations for specific Guggenheim Fellowship applications, have been appraised out of this collection. 1 blank optical disc has been discarded.
  - Hello Jack, 2017-2020 (Box 78, Box 79, Box 80, Box 81)
  - A Dark Matter, 2009-2010 (Box 81, Box 82, Box 83)
  - The Skylark, 2007-2008 (Box 83, Box 84, Box 85, Box 86, Box 87)
  - In the Night Room, 2005-2006 (Box 87, Box 88, Box 89)
  - The Green Woman, 2007 (Box 89, Box 90, Box 91)
  - The Process (is a Process All its Own), 2016 (Box 91)
  - American Fantastic Tales, 2009 (Box 92, Box 93, Box 94)
  - Poe's Children, 2008 (Box 94, Box 95)
  - At the Foot of the Story Tree, Bill Sheehan, 1998 (Box 95)
  - Five Stories, 2007 (Box 95)
  - Near/Miss, 2018 (Box 95)
  - Manuscripts for Various Works, 1995-2015 (Box 96, Box 97)
  - Literary Events, Press, Correspondence, 1993-2018 (Box 97)
  - Book Inventory, Calendars, Photographs, Stoker Weekend, 1990-2021 (Box 98)
  - Published Books, 1998-2001 (Box 98, Box 99, Box 100)
- Series XVII: 2023 Accretion, 2015, 2018-2020; 3.5 Linear Feet in 8 manuscript boxes
  This accretion to the Peter Straub Papers consists of bound manuscripts in various stages. These manuscripts include A Dark Matter, An Upstate Story, A Special Place, What Happens in Hello Jack, excerpts from Five Stories, Interior Darkness: Selected Stories, and excerpts from Magic Terror. This accretion also includes correspondence, notebooks, financial ledgers, and literary purchase agreements from movie production studios.
  This series has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
  - Readercon 26 Souvenir Program, 2015 (Box 101)
  - Manuscripts and Bound Drafts, circa 2015-2020 (Box 101, Box 102, Box 103, Box 104, Box 105)
  - Notebooks, circa 2015-2020 (Box 105, Box 106, Box 107, Box 108)
  - Correspondence, 2018-2020 (Box 106, Box 107)
- Oversize Series I: Works by Peter Straub, 1978-2005
  Includes oversize materials that were physically seperated from Series I.
  - Subseries B: Poetry, Short Fiction, Fragments of Unpublished Work, undated
    - Poetry, Short Fiction, Fragments of Unpublished Work, undated (Box 65)
  - Subseries C: Essays, Articles, Lectures, 2003
    - Essays, Articles, Lectures, 10/2003 (Box 66)
  - Subseries E: Galleys and Proofs, 1978-2001
    - Galleys and Proofs, 11/1978 (Box 63)
      Ghost Story Proofs.
    - Galleys and Proofs, 03/1983 (Box 65)
    - Galleys and Proofs, 03/1983; 08/2001 (Box 66)
  - Subseries G: Periodicals, 2005
    - Periodicals with PS work, 01/1983-12/1984; 01/1990 (Box 65)
    - Periodicals with PS work, 06/05/2005 (Box 66)
- Oversize Series III: Correspondence, 1998-2004; undated
  Includes oversize materials that were physically seperated from Series III.
  - Correspondence, 04/1998; 11/1998; 04/2000; 10/2001; 10/2004 (Box 65)
  - Correspondence, 11/1999; undated (Box 66)
- Oversize Series IV: Administrative Files, 1976-1988
  Includes oversize materials that were physically seperated from Series IV.
  - Administrative File, 05/1976; 08/1978-10/1979; 01/1981; 1987-1988 (Box 65)
  - Administrative File, 03/1983 (Box 66)
- Oversize Series V: Personal Files, 1966-2004
  Includes oversize materials that were physically seperated from Series V.
  - Subseries C: Miscellaneous Personal, 1966-2004
    - Miscellaneous Personal, 1966; 2004 (Box 65)
    - Miscellaneous Personal, 2003 (Box 66)
- Oversize Series VI: Reviews and Publicity, 1985-1999; undated
  Includes oversize materials that were physically seperated from Series VI.
  - Reviews and Publicity, undated (Box 64)
  - Reviews and Publicity, 02/03/1985; 1988; 12/1989; 10/1990; 01/1996; 08/1999; undated (Box 65)
  - Reviews and Publicity, 2007 (Box 66)
  - Reviews and Publicity, 1991 (Folder 3 Left)
- Oversize Series VII: Work by Others, 2006; undated
  Includes oversize materials that were physically seperated from Series VII.
  - Subseries A: Work by Others, 2006; undated
    - Work by Others, 2006; undated (Box 66)
- Oversize Series VIII: Periodicals and Clippings, 1969-2007
  Includes oversize materials that were physically seperated from Series VIII.
  - Periodicals and Clippings, 1993; 1995 (Box 65)
  - Periodicals and Clippings, 09/05/1969; 1988; 1990; 1991; 1992; 1999; 07/30/2000; 07/2000; 07/2007 (Box 66)